### **Daniel Wilkinson**

Kenbridge, Va 23944

Phone: 434-233-2942 | Email: dcwilkinson@wilktech.com

LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/daniel-c-wilkinson/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/daniel-c-wilkinson/</a> | Github: <a href="https://github.com/DanWilk">https://github.com/DanWilk</a> Portfolio: <a href="https://danwilk.github.io/react-portfolio/">https://danwilk.github.io/react-portfolio/</a>

#### Summary

Full stack developer with a background in electrical installation and maintenance driven by a passion to learn and work on new projects. Possess skills in HTML, React.js, JavaScript, and both NoSql and MySql databases as well as many other languages and Node packages. Being a former electrician grants experience in troubleshooting and problem-solving to efficiently create applications using the MERN stack.

#### **Technical Skills**

Front-End: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, React

Back-End: Node.js, Express.js, MongoDb, MySQL, GraphQL, Handlebars, Webpack, Redux, Jest

#### **Projects**

Weather App | Repository: https://github.com/DanWilk/weather-app | Deployed: https://danwilk.github.io/weather-app/

- An application that utilizes 3rd party API's in order to show weather based on location. This application also has the ability to save the user's previous searches for the user's ease of use.
- Sole Developer
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, and 3rd party APIs

## Lorem Sipsum | Repository: https://github.com/cshepscorp/lorem-sipsum | Deployed: https://cshepscorp.github.io/lorem-sipsum/

- A web application utilizing multiple 3rd party API's in order to show a user multiple breweries, restaurants, and events within a locality specified by the user.
- Front-End Developer
- HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, 3rd party API's

# Band Gogh | Repository: https://github.com/SamuraiHuey/band-gogh | Deployed: https://band-gogh.herokuapp.com/

- This is a web application that utilizes a MySQL database in order to allow band members to post information about their band. People looking for local bands are also able to look through this site and see upcoming events
- Back-end Developer
- Handlebars, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, Express.js, MySQL, Sequelize

# Greg's List | Repository: https://github.com/mtlankenau/gregs-list Deployed: https://gregs-list-1.herokuapp.com/

- A MERN stack web application that allows users to create an account and then post jobs or services needed with their contact information posted as well as for non-logged-in users to find these posts.
- I was responsible for building the back-end and database along with another team member. I was also a large part of the error handling and troubleshooting the front end REACT.js
- REACT.js, Javascript, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, GraphQL, JWT's

#### **Experience**

Trilogy Education Virginia (Remote)

Read and troubleshoot code in order to assist students with learning coding fundamentals. Read and understand multiple coding languages in order to properly grade assignments

Recommended by instructional staff during my full stack development course for this position

### Maintenance Electrician PalletOne

June 2020-Present Chase City, Va

Maintain and repair electrical systems and components. Understand complicated documentation in order to effectively assist in troubleshooting. Must be able to effectively and efficiently solve problems at a moment's notice.

- Learned the skills of welding, hydraulic maintenance, and pneumatic maintenance quickly through on the job experience.
- One of two employees chosen to participate in leadership courses in partnership with the local community college.
- Assisted in designing and developing several pieces of equipment and tools that help complete normal daily tasks in a much more timely manner.

### Apprentice/Unlicensed Electrician M.C. Dean

April 2019- May 2020 Washington D.C./Boydton, Va

Must be able to comprehend and follow electrical diagrams and blueprints. Construct pipe assemblies and supports within a given deadline. Terminate wire and install devices in compliance with electrical code.

- Led a group of seven employees in order to reroute electrical wiring and amend blueprints based as a result of changes within the job specifications.
- Trained and Guided a team of four inexperienced employees in order to complete branch circuits that needed to be installed before the end of a close deadline at a rate of five complete circuits a day.
- Managed inventory for an entire project and requested orders based on material needed

# Senior Cook U.S.A Pizza and Wing Factory

April 2018-April 2019 Blackstone, Va

Cook food based on orders and customer wants. Maintain refrigerators and other kitchen equipment in order to keep business running. Able to keep all ingredients correctly dated and organized.

- Trained three new employees to cook and maintain the kitchen.
- Trusted by the owner to assist with business decisions, advertising, and specialties.
- Helped determine a new process to reduce the amount of time to correctly get orders to customers by nearly 50%.

### Apprentice Electrician B&M Electrical, HVAC, and Plumbing

September 2017- April 2018 Crewe, Va

Ability to troubleshoot and repair electrical equipment. Keep the work area clean and be respectful towards clients. Present myself in a professional manner while speaking with potential clients.

- Learned several troubleshooting processes for heating, air conditioning, and electrical equipment.
- Served a minimum of one customer per day to include unit removal and installation

#### Education

#### Bootcamp Certificate: University of Richmond Coding Bootcamp remote

Full Stack web development course specializing in MERN stack applications. Learned the fundamentals of HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Node.js, Jest testing and many other tools and useful node packages.